August 10th, 2010
of the Imperial Calendar.
皇歴2010年8月10日
The Holy Britannian Empire
declared war upon Japan.
神聖ブリタニア帝国は
日本に宣戦布告した
In the face of the Knightmare Frame,
Britannia's newest weapon,
ブリタニアの最新兵器
ナイトメアフレームの前に
Japan could not stand for even
one month before it was defeated.
一月と持たずに敗れ去った日本は
Its freedom and traditions,
rights and honor...
自由と伝統 権利と誇り
そして名前を奪われた
and finally even its name
were taken from it.
Eleven.
イレヴン
That number became
the new name for the Japanese.
その数字が新しい日本人の名前だった
Jibun wo sekai sae mo
The moment when I might be able...
自分を 世界さえも 変えてしまえそうな
Kaete shimae sou na shunkan wa
To change myself and even the world
瞬間は 何時も直ぐ傍に…
Itsumo sugu soba ni
It's always right there at my side
Kakusenu iradachi to
Even as I stood still, looking at myself
隠せぬ苛立ちと
立ち尽くす自分を 見つめ
Tachitsukusu jibun wo mitsume
With undisguised frustration
Mayoi nagara nayami nagara
Feeling lost, feeling anguished
迷いながら 悩みながら
Kuyami nagara kimereba ii sa
Feeling mournful, deciding what to do
悔やみながら 決めればいいさ
Kimi ga kureta kotoba hitotsu
All it took was a single word from you
君がくれた 言葉ひとつ
Tomadoi wa kiesari
And my uncertainty vanished
戸惑いは消え去り
Karappo datta boku no heya ni hikari ga sashita
You let the light shine into what was my empty room
からっぽだった 僕の部屋に 光が射した
Miageta oozora ga
The sky I had been looking up at...
見上げた大空が 青く澄み切って行く
Aoku sumikitte yuku
Cleared and turned blue
Tozashita madowo hiraku
And I decided to throw open...
閉ざした 窓を 開く事を決めた
Koto kimeta
The windows that were kept closed
Jibun wo sekai sae mo
The moment when I might be able...
自分を 世界さえも 変えてしまえそうな
Kaete shimae sou na shunkan wa
To change myself and even the world
瞬間を 感じる今ここに…
Kanjiru ima koko ni
I feel it right here with me
THE FALSE CLASSMATE
どういう事だ イレヴンを逃がせとは
What's the idea of
letting the Elevens escape?!
回収すべきガスも
まだ残っているのだろう
Don't we still have to recover
the poison gas that they stole?!
しかし クロヴィス殿下の指示ですから
But we were ordered
to by Prince Clovis!
バトレー将軍は？
What about Gen. Bartley?!
I want to ask the general staff about all this!
参謀府の意見を聞きたい
将軍達は席を外されたようで
It looks like Gen. Bartley
and the others have left their posts.
では コンタクト・フロアーには
殿下のみだと？
You mean Prince Clovis is the only
one manning the conduct floor?!
う うれしいよ ルルーシュ
日本占領の時に死んだと聞いてたから
I... I'm so glad, Lelouch!
I heard you had died
during the capture of Japan.
やあ よかった 生きていて
どうだい 私と本国に
What good news that you're alive!
Why don't you come back
to the homeland with me?
また外交の道具とする気か
You intend to use me as
a tool of diplomacy again?
お前は何ゆえ俺達が道具になったか
忘れたようだな
It seems you've forgotten why we
were used as tools in the first place.
うっ
そう…
Right.
母さんが 殺されたからだ
Because my mother was killed.
母の身分は騎士侯だったが 出は庶民だ
Mother held the title of Knight of Honor,
but she was originally a commoner.
他の皇女達にとっては
さぞや目障りな存在だったんだろうな
No doubt the other empresses
held her in contempt.
しかし… だからといって
テロリストの仕業に見せかけてまで
Even so...
Even though you made it look
like the work of terrorists...
母さんを殺したな！
You people killed my mother!
私じゃない！
It wasn't me! I swear, it wasn't!
私じゃないぞ！
なら 知っている事を話せ
俺の前では 誰も嘘はつけない
Then tell me what you know.
No one can lie to me now!
誰だ 殺したのは？
Who killed her?!
う…
第二皇子シュナイゼルと
第二皇女コーネリア
Schneizel, the second prince,
and Cornelia, the second princess.
彼らが知っている
They know.
うっ
あいつらが首謀者か？
They're the ringleaders?
そこまでは知らないか
That's all that you know, huh?
うっ…
うわっ！
ほ 本当に私じゃない！
やってない！　やらせてもいない！
It... It wasn't me, I swear!
I didn't kill her! I didn't have her killed!
分かったよ
I understand.
しかし
However...
や やめろ！
腹違いとはいえ 実の兄だぞ！
No, don't! We may have different mothers,
but I'm still your brother!
きれい事で 世界は変えられないから
You can't change the world
without getting your hands dirty.
こーら ルルーシュ！
Wake up, Lelouch!
今 寝てたでしょ？　手が止まってた
You were asleep just now!
Your hand stopped moving!
だからって叩かないで下さいよ
So? You don't have to
beat me up about it!
俺を置き去りにした罰だって
It's punishment
for ditching me before!
そうそう　何やってたのよ 昨日
Yeah, that's right.
What were you up to yesterday?
ああ いや…
Uh, nothing...
はいはいはい
All right, all right, all right!
話を脱線させないの！
I won't allow you to change the subject!
今は部活の予算審査
とっとと済ませないと
If we don't review the club activity budget now,
there won't be a budget for anything, will there?
どこも予算が おりないでしょ
そんな事になったら
And if that happens...
馬術部なんか マジ怒り
また ここに突入して来たりして
The horseback riding club
will be be pissed off at us!
They'll come busting in here again!
え…
リヴァル あんたも一応
生徒会メンバーなんだから
Rivalz, can't you take being a student
council member more seriously?
せめて もう１日早く思い出して
くれていれば良かったんですよ
You should have reminded us
about the deadline a day earlier.
もう１日遅く が正解 諦めがつく
I'd have preferred a day later.
Then we'd have given up already.
いい考えだ 今からでも
Good idea. For now, at least.
ガーッツ！
GUTS!
ああ…
またガッツの魔法ですか？
Casting your Guts! Spell again?
は～い あなた方は
頑張りたくなりま～す
Yup!
Don't you want to work harder now?
かかりませんよ
そんなインチキ魔法じゃ
A fake spell like that will never work.
会長！　私 かかった事にします！
I'll pretend it's working on me, Prez!
うん！　肉体派は素直でよろしい
Good! A sound body leads to a sound mind, I see.
鍛えてるって言ってくれないと
Well, we practice a lot, so...
うふっ そうじゃなくてさあ
That's not what I meant.
う？
立派じゃん
You're impressive.
え？
この間 女子寮のバスルームで確かめた
I checked you out lately in the girls' bathroom.
トップとアンダーの
バランスがいいよね
You're filling out nicely on the
top and bottom, aren't you?
ほほ
Oh, ho?
な 何 言ってるんですか　変態！
Wh-What are you
talking about, you pervert!
もう！　会長って中身は
絶対おじさんだよね！
I swear! The prez is a dirty
old man on the inside!
自分で話を そらしていくし
Just bending the conversation
to her advantage like that!
ミレイちゃんは昔から ああなんで…
Milly's always been like that, though.
あっはっはっ…
まあ 予算表 間に合ったんだし
いいじゃないの
Well, we've finished the budget plan
right on time, so let's not complain.
毒ガステロだって！
The terrorists used poison gas?!
あ…
怖いよなあ シンジュクなんて
30分と離れてないのに
That's scary! Shinjuku's only 30 minutes away from here!
私 見た
シンジュクの方で煙が上がってるの
I saw it! There was smoke rising from the direction of Shinjuku.
あれ毒ガスだったんだ
That must have been the poison gas!
シンジュクの様子 他に出てない？
Anything else on what's
going on over there?
シンジュク？
Shinjuku?
昨日 この件で電話したんだよ
知り合いからリアルタイムで聞いてて
I phoned you about it yesterday.
I was hearing about it in
real time from a friend of mine.
おい 画像アップされてっぞ
イレヴンの死体が！
Hey, check out the footage
of those dead Elevens!
いやあ！　見せないで！
Agh! Don't look at them!
おかしい… なぜ あの情報を隠す？
Strange... Why would they
hide the news about it?
うううう…！
う！
クロヴィスの死を隠すという事は
混乱を防ぐ為か？
Are they hiding Clovis's death
to guard against chaos?
しかし それをやる という事は
発表する時に
But if they do that,
then when they announce it...
ふ… 我ながら細い神経だな
I'm a lot more sensitive than I thought.
ぬるいな 文官出のやる事は
That ex-bureaucrat's response
is tepid at best.
バトレー将軍ですか？
You mean Gen. Bartley?
犯人は あれだけの警備を
２度も突破している
The murderer broke into
high-security areas twice.
こんな型通りの検問では
Such a perfunctory inspection
won't find him!
ジェレミア辺境伯
Margrave Jeremiah, now that Prince
Clovis is dead, we Purebloods can...
クロヴィス殿下亡き今 私達 純血派が
指示は私が出す
内部をまとめるまで待て
I'll give the directions.
Wait till I've gotten everyone on our side.
カレン！　久しぶり！
Kallen! It's been ages!
体 いいの？
Are you okay?
ソフィちゃん 心配してたよ
Sophie's been worried about you.
もう大丈夫なの？
You're okay now?
うん
あんまり無理は できないけどね
Yes, although I can't strain myself.
あ！
そうか 引っ掛かった訳だ
Of course.
I thought she looked familiar.
だって あんまり休むと
みんなに ついて行けなくなっちゃうし
After all, if I take too much time off,
I'll never be able to keep up with everyone.
ルルーシュくん 何 見てるのかな？
Whatcha looking at,
my dear Lelouch?
ひょっとして惚れちゃった？
Might you have a crush on her?
珍しいだけだよ
Just thinking this is a rare event.
彼女 始業式以来 来てなかったよな
She hasn't been here
since the term started.
カレン・シュタットフェルト
Kallen Stadtfeld.
そ～れ！
There we go!
なんか 体が弱いらしくてさあ
前の学年でも たまにしかね
I hear she isn't well.
She was barely in school last year, too.
でも 成績は抜群に優秀
Still, her grades are at the top of the class.
シュタットフェルト家のご令嬢だから
金はあるし 性格も穏やか
Since she's a daughter of the Stadtfeld family,
she's got wealth and a gentle disposition.
いやあ お目が高い
Man, you have high standards!
違うって
It's not like that.
隠さない 隠さない
まあ ちょっと箱入り過ぎるけどね
Oh, don't hide it!
She's a touch too sheltered, if you ask me.
キャア～ッ！
蜂よ！　蜂が！
A bee! There's a bee!
え？
カレンさん 逃げて！
Kallen, run!
キャーッ！
ん…
早く逃げて！
Hurry and run!
キャアア～ッ！
こんな所に蜂だなんて
What's a bee doing in here?
蜂の巣でも あるのかしら
I wonder if there's a hive nearby.
んっ！
ああ～ イライラする！
病弱なんて設定にしなきゃよかった
Oh, this pisses me off!
I wish I didn't have to act
like a freaking invalid!
んっ
ん…
ヤバ 見られた
Crap! He saw me!
やはり あの時の女だ
It had to be her!
な 何か用かしら？
C- Can I help you?
質問に答えろ
Answer my questions.
はい
Yes.
昨日 シンジュクで
グラスゴーに乗っていたな？
Were you the pilot of that Glasgow
in Shinjuku yesterday?
はい
Yes.
どうしてテロを？
Why are you a terrorist?
私は日本人だから
ブリタニアの血も半分 入ってるけど
Because I'm Japanese.
Although I am technically half-Britannian.
えっ ハーフ？　しかし なぜそこまで
A half-breed?!
But why go that far?
はっ！
ええっと… 私に何か？
Um... Did you want something?
いや もう用は済んだ
No. I'm through here.
そうだ 念の為
Right. Just to be sure...
シンジュクの事は何も言うな
Don't say anything about
what happened in Shinjuku.
えっ？　シンジュクって どういう事？
What do you mean in Shinjuku?
うっ
どうしてそんな事 言うの？
What makes you mention that?
教室に戻れ
Return to the classroom.
あなたが質問に答えてくれたらね
Only if you answer that question!
効かない？　どういう事だ これは…
It's not working?!
What's going on here?!
う う…
ルルー！
Lulu! Kallen!
あっ
カレンさ～ん！
次 理科準備室だよ！
急がないと！
We have to go to the
science prep room next!
Get a move on!
やっべ！
実験器具 出さなくっちゃ！
Crap! I've got to set up
the experiment equipment!
ああ
Um...
しくじった しかし…
It didn't work? But...
どうしましょう 今日も遅いかも
What shall we do?
He may be late again tonight.
待ちます
夕食は一緒にって言ってたから
I'll wait. He said
we'd eat dinner together.
ほら できましたよ
Look, it's all done.
あっ？
あ… 鳥？
A bird?
はい 鶴です
Right. It's a crane.
すごい 日本人って器用なのねえ
Amazing.
Japanese people are so skillful!
うふふ…
ええっ
ナナリー様？　あ…
Miss Nunnally?
ごめん 遅れちゃって
Sorry I'm so late.
お帰りなさい お兄様
Welcome home, big brother!
お帰りなさいませ
Welcome home, sir.
ただいま ナナリー 咲世子さん
I'm home, Nunnally. Sayoko.
諸君も知っての通り計画は全て失敗した
As you already know,
the project was a complete failure.
ゆえに この研究所を破棄する
Consequently, I am disbanding
this research center.
え？　しかし
Wha?! But!
ナリタに場所を用意した　全て移す
I've set up
a place in Narita for you.
Move everything out there.
記憶がないとはいえ 私や参謀達が
クロヴィス殿下の元を離れたのは事実だ
While none of us
remember doing so,
the fact is that I and the other staff
officers left Prince Clovis on his own.
私は本国に戻され責任を問われるだろう
I'll very likely be recalled to the
homeland to take responsibility for that.
その際 皇帝陛下に秘密で
この実験を進めていた事が知られると
If His Majesty learns
that this experiment...
has proceeded without
his knowledge when I do!
分かりました 早急に準備を進めます
Understood, sir!
We'll make preparations as fast as we can!
さっきね
Miss Sayoko was just
teaching me about origami.
咲世子さんに
折り紙を教えてもらったんです
１枚の紙を何度も折ると
鳥とか船とか色んな物になるんですって
When you fold a piece
of paper over and over,
you can make birds and boats
and all sorts of things!
あ…
ああ そんなに急いで話さなくても
大丈夫だよ
Uh-oh.
You really don't have to talk so fast.
俺は どこにも行かないから
I'm not going anywhere.
ありがとう お兄様
Thank you, big brother.
どういたしまして
You're very welcome.
ふふ… 良かった
I'm so glad.
え？
お兄様 昨日の夜 何か怖かったから
You sort of scared me last night.
そうかい？　ごめん…
ちょっと考え事があってさ
Did I? Sorry. I had something to think about.
ねえ
So...
ん？
この鶴を千羽 折るとね
願いが叶うんですって
They say if you fold a thousand
cranes, your wish comes true.
もしお兄様に叶えたい事があるのなら…
So, if you have anything to wish for...
いやぁ 俺は…
Oh, no. Not me.
ナナリーは？　何かないのかい？
And you, Nunnally? Do you wish for anything?
う～ん… 優しい世界でありますように
I wish the world was a gentle place.
お前の目が見えるようになる頃には
きっと そうなってるよ
When you can see again,
I'm sure it will be.
本当に？
Really?!
約束する
I promise.
そうだ　俺達には選択できる未来が
限られている
That's right.
There are few futures which are open to us.
ここで匿われている といっても
While they may be sheltering us here,
アッシュフォード家が
いつまで 後ろ盾になってくれるか
will the Ashford family always
be there to back us up?
素性がバレたらシャーリーや
リヴァル達だって離れるだろうし
If our identity was ever revealed, even Shirley
and Rivalz and the others would abandon us.
行く末は 政治の道具か陰謀の餌食だ
Our fate is to be either political tools or
the prey of other peoples' conspiracies.
作らねば
I have to make it.
ナナリーだけでも幸せに過ごせる世界を
Make a world where
Nunnally can live happily.
ん？
この前 教えてもらったの
日本の約束の仕方
She taught me about this before.
It's how the Japanese make a promise.
嘘ついたら針千本 飲ーます 指切った
Cross my heart, hope to die,
eat a thousand needles if I lie.
I swear!
うふっ
あ… 怖いな
千本も針を飲まなくちゃいけないのか
Now I'm scared! I may have to eat
a thousand needles someday!
そ だから嘘ついたら いけないんですよ
Uh-huh! So you'd better not be lying.
大丈夫 俺は嘘をつかないよ
It's okay. I'm not lying.
お前にだけは
Not to you, at least.
CODE GEASS
Lelouch of the Rebellion
This is the only weapon I have.
これだけが俺の武器だ
知らなくては 使い方を
And I don't even know how to use it.
ルルーシュ
Lelouch!
あ
もうすぐ授業が始まるぞ
Class will be starting soon.
あ はい
Oh. Yes, sir.
先生 今度の論述試験の問題
教えて下さいよ
Sir, could you please tell me what
questions will be on our essay exam?
エディンバラの屈辱と新大陸への遷都
北南戦争についてだ
They'll cover The Humiliation of Edinburgh,
"The Transfer of the Capitol to the New World,"
and "The North-South War."
この力 なくなった訳ではないのか
So, I haven't lost this power after all?
うっ
先生
Sir!
ん？
今度の論述試験の問題 教えて下さいよ
Could you please tell me what
questions will be on our essay exam?
冗談言ってないで真面目に勉強しろ
お前は やればできるんだからな
Quit joking around
and study seriously!
You can handle them
if you make the effort.
は～い
Right!
やはりな　同じ人間には
１度しか効かないって訳か
As I suspected. It can only
work once on the same person.
どうだい 久しぶりの学校は？
So, how's life at
your dear old school?
窮屈…
Stifling.
昨日なんて歴史の授業だし
ねえ そっちに戻った方が
I had history class yesterday.
Look, maybe I should head back to you.
今は軍の警戒が厳しい
The army's on high alert right now.
しばらくは
そこで ほとぼりを冷ますんだ
Stay there and let things cool down.
でも あの声の事だって
But what about the voice on the radio?
声だけじゃ探しようがないよ
You can't go looking for a voice. Besides...
それにカレンが学生やってる方が
ナオトも喜ぶ
Naoto would be happy that you're a student again.
ん
シンジュクの事は しばらく忘れろ
また連絡する
Forget what happened in Shinjuku
for now. I'll contact you again later.
シンジュク… 分かってるけど
Shinjuku... I understand, but!
はっ！
シンジュクの事は何も言うな
Don't say anything about
what happened in Shinjuku.
まさか あの時の声
Is it possible that was his voice?
１つは貴族教育です
First of all, there was the education of the aristocracy.
統治する人間を特定し
By concentrating on the ruling class
with intensive education and training,
集中的に教育 訓練する事で
優れた統治者を育てる
a superior breed of ruler was produced.
２つ目はスピードです 選りすぐられた…
The second point was speed.
似てる… か？　いや
声の記憶なんて あてにならないけど
It's similar... Or is it?
No. I don't remember the voice well enough to be sure!
はい よろしい
All right, that will do.
偉大なるエリザベス１世の
お子であるヘンリー９世の即位によって
With the ascension of Henry the 9th, son of the
great Elizabeth the 1st, the golden age of...
テューダー朝は隆盛を…
与えたのはシンジュクという情報だけだ
しかし…
All I gave her was knowledge
I know about Shinjuku. However...
もし 私の正体を知られていたら
If he knows who I really am...
早いうちに
Then as soon as possible...
処理しなければ
I need to take care of him.
研究所は？
And the research center?
昨晩のうちにはナリタに
It was transferred to Narita last night.
そうか…
I see.
申し訳ありません 殿下
Forgive me, Your Highness.
ハーブティーの専門店なの
It specializes in herb tea.
It's really fantastic!
すっごく素敵なとこ
カレンさんも おいでよ…
You should come too, Kallen.
ねぇルル この後さあ
Say Lulu, we're about to head over to...
悪い また今度な
Sorry. Maybe next time.
あ やっぱり？
Oh, I knew it.
カレンさん自宅通いなんだ
Kallen has to go straight home, huh?
門限とかあるの？
You have a curfew?
あ
何？
What?
ちょっと付き合ってくれないか
話したい事がある
Could you come with me, please?
I'd like to talk to you.
え
ええ！
ええ
Yes.
誘ってくれると思ってた
I was expecting you'd ask me to.
はあ？
キャ～！
お分かりですか　私達の決意を
Do you understand
our determination now?!
B- But, I told you!
だっ だから私は！
覚えていない？
まだそんな つまらぬ言い訳を
You don't remember?
You still cling to that
pathetic excuse of yours?!
他の者にも聞け！　証言なら…
Ask the others!
If you want the testimony...
我が身 大事か 見苦しい！
Ducking the blame!
You're a disgrace!
あなたが これ以上
殿下のお傍に居るのは 許されない
I won't allow you to remain at
His Highness's side any longer!
学校内に こんな場所があったなんて
I never knew there was anyplace
like this in the school.
生徒会専用のクラブハウスだ
It's the club house for use
by the student council.
舞踏会なんかも できるように
広めに造ってある
It was built large enough
to host a formal dance.
ここなら邪魔は入らない？
And we won't be disturbed in here?
そういう事だ
Exactly.
あった～！
There it is!
あ
あった あった！　ほら
Found it! Found it! Look, it's this, right?
これでしょ？
ああ それです　実験データ
Ah! That's it! The experiment data.
やれやれ 腰痛え
Oh, man... My back hurts now.
そっち見つかった？
Did you find it?
こっちも できたから 始めよっか
I'm through on my end,
so why don't we start?
おお すげえ！
Whoa! Amazing!
さっすがミレイさん！
Way to go, Milly!
うっふふ… もっと褒めるがよい
Please, you can compliment me more!
あの… なんですか？　これ
Um... What is all this?
知ってて
連れて来てくれたんじゃなかったの？
Didn't you bring her here because you knew?
カレンさん生徒会に入れるから
It's because we're letting
Kallen into the student council.
は…
お爺ちゃんに頼まれちゃってさあ
My grandfather asked us to.
理事長に？
The school principal did?
うん 体の事もあるから
普通に部活は難しいだろうって
Yeah. He says it would be
hard for her to participate in...
regular club activities
because of her health problems.
あ 私 生徒会長のミレイ
よろしくね
Oh! I'm Milly, the council president.
How do you do?
あ… よろしくお願いします
Oh. Uh, it's a pleasure to meet you.
俺 リヴァル　書記ね
分からない事があったら なんでも聞いて
I'm Rivalz, the secretary.
If there's anything you
don't understand, just ask me.
シャーリーです
水泳部と掛け持ちだけど よろしく
I'm Shirley, and I'm also
in the swim club. How do you do?
わ… 私… ニーナです
And, I'm Nina.
あ いえ こちらこそ
Um, uh, a pleasure.
あの…
Um, excuse me Shirley, but could
you put these on the table for me?
シャーリーさん
すみません これ テーブルに
あ ありがとう ナナちゃん
Oh, thanks, Nunna!
ナナリー お前まで
Nunnally. You, too?
ん
ルルーシュの妹よ
This is Lelouch's little sister.
私は中等部なので
生徒会じゃないんですけど
I'm in the middle school group,
so I'm not in the student council.
いいでしょ 準会員って事で
That's okay.
You're an associate member, right?
うん
Right.
カレンさん よろしくお願いします
It's a pleasure to meet you, Kallen.
よろしく こちらこそ
It's a pleasure for me, too.
さて まずは乾杯といきますか
Okay then! First, shall we drink a toast?
あ シャンパン！
Champagne!
生徒会 自ら これはまずいんじゃ
Student council members can't drink!
まあまあ 堅い事言わないで
Oh, loosen up, you guys!
ダメに決まってるでしょ！
We're not allowed to drink that!
なんですか？
What's happening?
ナナリーはこっちね
You have this, Nunnally.
ルルーシュ パス！
Lelouch, catch!
あ！
え
あ もう！
Oh, for heaven's sake!
ルルも簡単に受け取らないの！
You're not getting away with this either, Lulu!
ああ！
ふっ
う！
うわ～ん
どうかしました？
What just happened?
着替えは？
A change of clothes?
咲世子さんが
Sayoko's getting them.
これだからブリタニアは… 全く！
That's why I hate Britannians.
For crying out loud...
あ
ルルーシュだ
It's Lelouch.
え
着替え 持って来たんだけど
I brought a change of clothes.
大丈夫 カーテン引いてるから
You can come in.
The shower curtain's closed.
ああ 悪いな… にぎやか過ぎる連中で
Um, sorry about this.
They can be a little too lively sometimes.
ううん　たまには
こういう無邪気な楽しさも悪くないわ
It's not bad to just have
a little fun once in a while.
着替え とりあえず俺のでいいか？
You mind if you change into
some of my clothes for now?
気にしない そういうのは
Don't worry about it.
早いのね
男子寮まで行って来たんでしょ
That was fast. You went all the
way to the boys' dorm and back?
俺 ここに住んでるから
I live here.
え？
寮で暮らすのは 妹には難しくてさ
It'd be hard for my
sister to live in the dorms.
理事長の好意で
ここに住まわせてもらってる
The school principal
lets us live here as a favor.
そう
I see.
それじゃ
Anyway...
あ 待って！
Wait!
取ってくれる？　そこのポーチ
Can you hand me
that pouch over there?
ああ
Sure.
んっ
えっ
思ったより活発なんだな
You're livelier than I expected.
あの日 シンジュクに居たの？
Were you in Shinjuku on that day?
なんの事だ
What do you mean?
とぼけないで
Don't play dumb!
なぜシンジュクって言ったの？
Why did you mention Shinjuku?
シンジュクだと何か都合が悪いのか？
Is there something wrong with Shinjuku?
質問に質問で答えないで！
Don't answer my question
with a question!
答えはイエスかノー
Is the answer yes or no?
それ以外は聞きたくない
I don't want to hear
anything else!
う…
出ないと誰か来ちゃうけど
If I don't answer it,
someone will come.
いいかな
All right?
はい アッシュフォード学園 生徒会
Hello. Ashford Academy student council.
え？　いや 俺は… はあ
No, I'm... Oh.
君あてだ
It's for you.
出れば分かるってさ
He says you'll know him
if you talk to him.
ん…
もしもし
Hello?
無事だったようだな Ｑ１
I'm glad you're alive and well, Q-1.
はっ！
違った…？
Was I wrong?
明後日の16時
The day after tomorrow, at 16:00.
あ
旧東京タワーの展望室に１人で来い
The observation deck of the
old Tokyo Tower. Come alone.
お前は誰だ
停戦命令を出させたのは…
Who are you?! How did you
arrange that cease-fire order?!
あっ おい！　切るな！
Hey! Don't hang up on me!
くっ…
なんだ 停戦命令って
What do you mean, cease-fire order?
あ
随分 物騒なお友達だな
Sounds like you have some
pretty dangerous friends.
あ 今のは その…
This was just...
当てようか
Shall I guess?
え
ゲームの話だろ？　ネットとかさ
It's about a game, right?
On the Net, right?
え ええ！　そうなの 私…
Uh... Yeah! That's it.
Because I've been shut up in my house.
家に こもりがちだったから
だから忠告したんだよ
シンジュクの事は言わない方がいいって
That's why I warned you before.
That bit about how you
shouldn't talk about Shinjuku.
いるんだ 君みたいな人に
わざと画像とか見せたがる奴らがさ
There are guys who'd intentionally show
a person like you footage of that stuff.
ところで…
Um, by the way... I can see you.
見えてるんだけど
え？
あ
ああ！
あの 誰にも言わないから
じゃあ後で
Um, I won't tell anyone!
Anyway, I'll see you later.
違ったんだ
I was wrong.
無事だったようだな Ｑ１
I'm glad you're alive and well, Q-1.
あ！
あれ…？
Huh?
生徒会っていっても
大して仕事はないんだ
The student council doesn't require much actual work.
たまに書類仕事があるくらいで
あとはイベントの企画
Beyond the occasional paperwork,
we also plan school events.
イベントって文化祭とか？
By events, you mean the cultural festival?
男女逆転祭りとか
Along with the Cross-Dressing Festival,
the Absolute Silence Party,
絶対無言パーティーとか
水着で授業とか
and Going to Class in Your Swimsuit Day.
なあに？　それ
What are those?
会長の趣味
Our president's weird tastes.
そのうち付き合わされるから
覚悟しとけよ
She'll get you involved in
this stuff soon, so be prepared.
お兄様 大変！
Big brother, it's awful!
なんだい？
What is it?
クロヴィス殿下が亡くなったのよ
Prince Clovis has died!
殺されたんだってさ！
They say he was killed!
え？
ん…
クロヴィス殿下は こうぎょされた
Prince Clovis has passed away!
イレヴンとの戦いの中で
平和と正義の為に
While fighting for peace and justice against the Elevens,
殉死されたのだ
he died a martyr!
我々は悲しみを押して
その遺志を継がなければならない
We all must push down our sorrow and carry on his will!
たった今 新しい情報が入りました
We've just received new information.
え？
実行犯と見られる男が拘束されました
The man suspected of
the murder has been captured.
ええっ！
発表によりますと
According to the report, the man arrested is an honorary Britannian.
逮捕されたのは名誉ブリタニア人です
まさか！
Can it be?!
枢木スザク一等兵
Private Suzaku Kururugi.
容疑者は元イレヴン
名誉ブリタニア人の枢木スザクです
The suspect is a former Eleven.
Honorary Britannian Suzaku Kururugi!
行けどもけものみち 獅子よ虎よと吠え
Yukedomo kemonomichi
Walking along the animal path
Shishi yotorayoto hoe
Roaring with the lions and tigers
茜射す空の 彼方にまほろば
Akane sasu sora no kanata ni mahoroba
Paradise lying far across a sky dyed red
幽囚の孤獨に 彷徨う青春は
Yuushuu no kodoku ni samayou seishun wa
To a youth wandering, imprisoned in loneliness
弱さと怒りが姿無き敵ですか
Yowasato ikari ga sugata naki teki desu ka
Are weakness and hatred shapeless enemies?
父よ 未だ我は
Chichi yo madaware wa
Oh father, I am still...
己を知りがたし
Onore wo shirigatashi
Learning who I am
先立つ兄らの
Sakidatsu anira no
As I pursue the backs I no longer see
見えない背中を追えば
Mienai senakawo oeba
Of the elder brothers who have gone before me
迷いの一夜に明星は誘う
Mayoi no hitoyo ni
In the night I spend lost
Myoujou wa izanau
The morning star beckons to me
死して終わらぬ
Shi shite owaranu
This will not end in my death
夢を焦がれども
Yume wo kogaredomo
I long for my dream
確かな君こそ我が命
Tashika na kimi kosowaga inochi
My faith in you sustains my life
烈風の荒野で 蝶よ花よと生き
Reppu no kouya de
In the windswept wilderness
Chou yo hanayoto iki
Living with the butterflies and flowers
とこしえの春に 咲き添うまぼろし
Tokoshie no haru ni sakisou maboroshi
Blooming together in a mirage of eternal Spring
混濁の純潔 この身は汚れても
Kondaku nojunketsu
If my purity seems muddied
Kono mi wayogoretemo
And my body seems filthy
心の錦を信じていてください
Kokoro no nishiki wo shinjiteite kudasai
Please believe in the finery within my heart
母よ けして我は
Hahayo kesshite ware wa namidawo misene domo
Oh mother, I will show no tears
涙を見せねども
足下の草に露は消えもせで
Ashimoto no
They vanish like...
Kusa ni tsuyu wa kiemosede
The dew in the grass beneath my feet
これは喜ぶべき事なのか？
スザクが生きていた
Is this something to be happy about?
Suzaku is still alive!
しかし なぜ？
But why has he been arrested in my place?
どうしてあいつが捕まっているんだ？
俺の代わりに
あいつを救わなければ
なんとしても
I have to save him, whatever it takes!
計画を前倒しにしてでも
Even if I have to rush my plan, I'll do it!
俺ならやれる！
やれるだけの力があるのだから
HIS NAME IS ZERO